Tales of a Gutsy Ninja -
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 1
鈴は２つだ。
There are two bells...
２つしかないってことは？
The fact that there are
only two bells means...
１人は 丸太か…。
(猿飛)察しがいいな 大蛇丸。
One person will lose...
You're very sharp, Orochimaru.
なぁ。 オレが鈴とったら
デートしてくれよ。
Say! If I get a bell,
you'll go out with me.
アンタが負けたら
もう つきまとわないで。
If you lose,
don't bother me anymore.
よっしゃ！ やったるで！
All right! I'll do it!
(自来也)スキだらけだぜ 今だ！
So many openings...
Now!
自来也 アンタとの賭け
勝ったわね。
I won the bet, Jiraiya!
You get to go to the log.
やっぱ アンタが丸太行き。
うるせえ！ 胸ペッタンコの
まな板綱手が！
Shut up, flat-chested plywood Tsunade!
んだと コラ！
このインテリエロ助が!!
What'd you say?!
You egg-headed perv!!
はいはい もういいから。
Now, now. That's enough...
綱手と大蛇丸は帰ってろ。
Tsunade and Orochimaru may go.
は～い。
フン。
Okay!
(猿飛)まったく お前は…。
You are hopeless...
忍者が バレバレの罠に
何度も引っかかるとは 何事か！
How can a ninja keep falling
into such obvious traps?!
だって…。
Can't help it...
お前に足りないのは
目的かのぉ。
Perhaps what you lack
is a purpose...
Huh?!
そうじゃのう…。
Let's see now...
おぉ あの手があるか。
Yes! We'll try this!
な 何だ!?
ま 慌てるな。 見ておれ。
Wh-What?!
Don't get so excited. Just watch.
忍法 口寄せ！
Ninja Art: Summoning Jutsu!
すげえ！
口寄せの術。
Awesome!
The Summoning Jutsu...
あらゆる生き物と
血で契約を交わしておき➡
You make a blood contract
with an animal,
好きなとき 自在に忍術で呼び出す
時空間忍術じゃ。
and summon them at any time
using the Transportation Technique.
オレも！
そいつと契約を結びたい！
I want to make a contract
with that one too!
そいつはムリじゃ。
That, you can't do.
Huh?
(猿飛)人の運命が
それぞれ違うように➡
In the same way that every man
is destined to a different fate,
契約できる生き物も
それぞれ 運命が決めてくれる。
so too is the animal to whom
he is intertwined.
Then which is my animal?
じゃあ
オレのはどいつだ？
契約の前に
もっと チャクラを練り➡
Before you can make a contract,
you need to be more adept
at molding chakra and sealing.
印の結び方を
勉強せねばならん。
え～っ また修業か…。
What? Not more training!
コラ！ 修業の中に
答えはあるのじゃ！
You will always find the answer
in your training!
＜目的をもった自来也は➡
Jiraiya had found a purpose
and from that day on,
その日から
マジメに修業を始めたが…＞
he began taking
his training seriously. However...
《もっと チャクラを練り➡
Mold more chakra...
印の結び方を勉強し…》
Study up on sealing...
時空間忍術を
マスターせねば！
I must master
the Transportation Technique...
この！
Dammit!
いつになったら
契約できるんだ？
When will I be able to
make a contract?
《オレ なんでこんな辛い修業を
してるんだ？》
Why do I put up with
this rough training?
((彼氏にするんなら やっぱ
インテリエロ助より 大蛇丸かな))
If I were to have a boyfriend,
I'd choose Orochimaru over
an egghead perv like you.
答えは単純だ！
The answer is simple!
最高の忍者になって 綱手のヤツを
振り向かせてみせるってこった！
I just have to become
the ultimate ninja
and sweep Tsunade off her feet!
そうとなりゃあ
ジッとしてるヒマなんかねえ!!
Now that that's settled,
there's no time to waste!
ほぉ～！
Ah...
忍としての目的に 気がついたか！
So he's discovered his purpose
for becoming a ninja.
《綱手だけじゃねえ。
And not just Tsunade,
きれいな姉ちゃんを 独り占めだ！
I'm gonna get all the pretty girls
to myself.
えっと… チャクラを集中させて…。
Let's see...
Concentrate my chakra and...
印は 亥 戌 酉 申 未…》
the seal is boar, dog,
bird, monkey, sheep...
待て！ 契約もせんで
時空間忍術を使っては➡
Wait! There's no telling
what will happen
if you use the Transportation Technique
without making a contract first!
何が起こるか わからん！
いっけ～!!
Go!
うわぁ～っ!!
ここは…。
Where am I...?
んっ？
あいや 待たれい！
Hold it right there!
そのケンカ この自来也様が買った!!
I, the great Master Jiraiya,
shall take over this fight!
ヘン！ ざっと こんなもんだ！
Heh! I guess that'll do!
(ブン太)ふむ 人間の子じゃ。
Hmmm...
A human child.
えっ!? ガ… ガマが しゃべった！
Huh?! A-A talking toad!
そっちこそ 人間のくせに
ホントに 妙木山に来よってからに。
And what about you?
To think, a human would really
come to Mount Myoboku...
どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?!
フカサク様～！
Lord Fukasaku!
人間の子でさぁ！
It's a human child.
(フカサク)おぉ 現れたか。
Oh...so you've arrived.
まるで オレが現れるのを
知ってたみたいだな。
You talk as though
you've been expecting me.
あぁ 知っておった。
Yes, I knew you were coming.
The Great Lord Elder predicted it.
大じじ様の予言でな。
((この妙木山に
１人の人間の子が 迷い込む。
A human child will stumble
into Mount Myoboku,
その子に ガマの力を与え
予言を与える。
and I will give that child the power
of the toad and a prophecy.
それが
ワシが ワシ自身のために見た夢…。
That is the dream which
I dreamt of myself...
(予言だったんじゃ))
My very own prophecy.
その人間が オレだったら➡
If that human is me...
then what is my  prophecy?!
与えてくれる予言って 何なんだ？
さぁな ワシは知らん。
Well... I don't know.
知らんって…。
Don't know?
お前は ここで修業しながら➡
You must stay here and train,
大じじ様の予言を待つのじゃ。
and wait for
the Great Lord Elder's prophecy.
ちょっ… ちょっと待てよ！
H-Hold it!
せっかく 強くなって
女の子に モテモテになろうってのに！
I made up my mind
to become strong
so that I'll be popular with women...
カエルにモテても しようがないぜ！
There's no point in getting popular
with frogs!
つべこべ 言うでない！
Quit complaining!
This is your destiny.
これが お前の運命じゃけえ！
運命だって!?
あぁ。
My destiny?!
Yes. You managed to come
to Mount Myoboku.
この妙木山に来ることができた。
これ すなわち➡
This is proof that you were indeed
the chosen one.
お前が
選ばれた運命の子という証拠だ！
《選ばれた人間か…。
The chosen one, eh?
ここで修業して
強くなるってのも➡
Training here and becoming strong...
That's pretty tempting too.
結構 捨てがたいかもしれないな》
＜ それ以来 自来也は
ガマの里 妙木山と➡
From this day forward,
Jiraiya divided his time between
Mount Myoboku, the land of toads,
and the Hidden Leaf Village...
木ノ葉隠れの里を
行き来しながら➡
仙人と忍術の修業を積む
少年時代を過ごしていった＞
He spent the days of his youth
in both Sage and ninjutsu training.
＜ しかし それは➡
However...
自来也が考えていたほど
甘いものではなかった＞
It was not to be as simple as
Jiraiya had thought.
《ここへ来て
確かに ワシは強くなった。
I've definitely gotten stronger
since coming here.
でも…。
But...
相変わらず 綱手は冷たい…。
Tsunade is as cold as ever.
いや… そもそも選ばれた運命を
持つ人間の目的が➡
Not just that...
If I was destined to be
the chosen one,
女の子に
モテることだけでいいのか…。
should my purpose simply
be to impress a girl?
それだけのために
ワシは強くなろうとしているのか》
Is that the only reason why
I'm trying to become strong?
(ブン太)自来也！ 自来也！
Jiraiya! Jiraiya!
おう！
Yeah?
自来也。 大じじ様が呼んじょる。
Jiraiya, the Great Lord Elder
has summoned you.
大ガマ仙人が？
はよ 行け。
The Great Lord Elder...?
Hurry up.
He has seen your prophecy!
お前への予言が出とんじゃ！
それ ホントか！ ブン太！
For real, Bunta?!
(自来也)お呼びで。
おぉ。
As summoned.
Ah, good. I'm glad you've come!
よう来た よう来た。
え？ 誰だったかいの？
Huh?
Who're you again?
大じじ様。
自来也ですじゃ 自来也！
Great Lord Elder, it's Jiraiya!
This is Jiraiya!
おぉ… そうじゃった
そうじゃった。
Oh, that's right! Right!
My, how you've grown...
大きゅうなったのぉ…。
(シマ)ったく
自分で呼んだくせにのぉ。
Gah, you're the one who summoned him,
ya great senile old geezer!
この大ボケじじいが！
母ちゃん。
Senile old geezer?!
大じじ様に向かって
大ボケじじいとは何じゃ！
Ma, how dare ya call
the Great Lord Elder a senile old geezer!
大ボケじじいとは！
コラ コラ ケンカはいけん。
Now now, let's not fight.
Spouses oughta get along...
夫婦は 仲ような。
ところで そこの…
誰じゃったかいの？
By the way...
Who're you, again?
自来也ちゃんよ… 大じじ様は➡
Jiraiya-boy.
The Great Lord Elder had
a dream about you.
お前の夢を見られたんじゃ。
お前も知ってのとおり
これは予言じゃ。
As you are aware,
it is a prophecy.
心して聞け。
はい。
So listen carefully.
Yes, sir!
では伝える… ワシの夢では➡
I shall now tell you.
In my dream...
エロいだけのお主も
いずれ 立派な忍になる。
you, who are solely pervy, will still
manage to become a splendid ninja.
そして 一人前に
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが…。
And in time, you will have
your own disciple...
《エロいだけって…
そういうことは➡
Solely pervy...?
Can't believe he remembers
that particular detail...
しっかり覚えてんだから ったく》
その弟子は 将来➡
That disciple will become a ninja
who will bring about a great change
忍の世に
大きな変革をもたらす忍になる。
to the ninja world.
夢では そう見えた。
変革？
That is what I saw in my dream.
A great change?
世に それまでにない
安定をもたらすか…。
Either great stability
or great destruction.
破滅をもたらすか…
その どちらかの変革じゃ。
The likes of which this world
has never seen before.
One of those two.
どちらかって…
どういうことですか？
One of those two?
What does that mean?
お主は その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
いずれ お主には大きな選択を
迫られる時が来るじゃろう。
The day will come when you will
be forced to make a critical selection.
選択？
Selection?
その選択次第で 世の変革が➡
Your choice shall decide
which way the change goes.
どちらに転ぶか
決まってしまうのじゃ。
ワシは… どうすればいいんですか？
正しく選択するには…。
What must I do...?
In order to make the right choice?
夢では 世界を歩いて
本を書いておったのぉ。
In my dream, you traveled the world,
writing books.
本？ なんで また…。
Books? Whatever for?
ワシにも 理由はわからんがの…。
I do not know either.
世界をめぐり 森羅万象を見て回る
ということじゃろうか。
Perhaps it will be a journey
around the world
to see all things in nature.
大じじ様の予言…
今までに はずれたことは？
Great Lord Elder, have your prophecies
ever not come to pass?
ないのぉ…。
No, never.
自来也。 いよいよ旅へ出るんか？
Jiraiya, you are leaving?
おぉ。 今のワシじゃ
変革者を導くことなんてできん。
Yup!
At this point in my life,
there's no way I can guide someone
who will be a revolutionary...
ましてや 正しい選択なんて
できるわけがない…。
Let alone make the right choice.
ふむ…。
もっと いろんなことを見て➡
Hmm...
I guess I need more time
to see many more things,
いろんな人と
出会う時間が必要なようじゃ。
and meet different people.
そうか…。
I see...
Just like in
the Great Lord Elder's dream,
まずは 大じじ様の
夢のままに世界を歩いて➡
I shall journey throughout the world
and perhaps, write a book.
本でも書くことにするさ。
It seems that is my destiny.
それが ワシの運命らしいからな。
＜自来也が
大ガマ仙人の夢の意味を求めて➡
While Jiraiya journeyed and
searched for the meaning
behind the Great Lord Elder's dream,
放浪の旅をしている頃➡
the state of the world grew
steadily more chaotic.
世の中は
次第に騒がしくなっていった。
The peace that had prevailed among
the Five Great Nations became fragile.
忍五大国の統治による
平穏も危うくなり➡
Aggression between lands
increased as did internal strife,
その揺らぎは
各国に侵略や内乱を呼び起こし➡
and the people began to suffer.
人々の生活をも脅かし始めた＞
お若いの なんで旅をしておる？
Young man...
Why are you traveling?
自分の運命を探してるんだ。
I'm searching for my destiny.
ほう。
ある方が見た夢のままに➡
Oh...?
Someone saw me in a dream.
And just like in that dream,
I journey from land to land.
世界を歩いている。
Oh my, what's the matter...?
おぉ どうした？
ひとつどうじゃ 乳アメじゃ。
Here, have one. It's milk candy.
傀儡？
ほう この子が言うておる。
A puppet?
Oh, this child tells me...
Destiny is not something you search for!
運命は探すものではない。
やってきた運命に
のっかるものだとな。
Destiny is something you latch onto
when it presents itself.
The age of war is coming.
戦乱のときが迫っておる。
Mechanical skills are useless
in times of peace,
平和なときには
役に立たぬカラクリの技も➡
but some feudal lord may pay
a high price for my services.
どこかの大名に
高く売れるかもしれん。
《あやつも また忍か…。
So he is a ninja too...
ヤツは破滅の時代の波にのることを
選択したんだのぉ。
He has chosen to ride the wave
to the age of destruction.
But that will only...
しかし それでは…》
Let's have more fun.
もっと楽しみましょうよ。
ねぇ。
う～ん…。
Come on.
Mmmm...
何を書いてるの？
What are you writing?
時代の波にのるだけじゃ➡
Just scribbling...
that riding on the wave of the times
will not result in the revolutionary
change needed for peace.
この世を今までなかったような➡
平和にするための変革は
ムリだってことをな…。
Say, say! If you're gonna
change something, change me!
ねぇねぇ
変えるなら私を変えてよ。
I suppose you're right.
That does sound more fun.
そうだのぉ
そのほうが楽しそうだ。
≪こんなのイカサマだ！
This is fraud!
こんなもんにカネなんか払えるか！
As if I'll pay for something like this!
あいや 待たれい！
Hold it right there!
このケンカ ワシが買った!!
I shall take over this fight!
Damn it!
クソッ！ 何て ひでえ運命だ。
How can fate be so cruel?!
I worked hard on cultivating the land
with what little knowledge I had.
一族復興のために
慣れぬクワを手に➡
All for the sake of my clan, and yet...
畑を耕してきたというのに。
《コイツ 今の世の流れに
不満を持っておるのか…》
So this fellow is dissatisfied with
the way the world is going...
どうだ 一献。
Have a drink...
ワシも自分の運命を
探しておるのだが➡
I've been searching for
my destiny too, but it's very elusive.
なかなか見つからん。
Humph... It's useless to search
for something like that.
フン… そんなもん探してもムダさ。
オレたち一族だけじゃ
大国の忍里にゃ➡
My people have no chance
against the ninja villages
of the Great Nations...
太刀打ちできねえ…。
《何だ コイツ
グチを言っとるだけかい》
This guy...
Is that all he can do...complain?
それは違うぞ。
うん？
You are wrong...
Huh?
I teach children in a village...
ボクは ある里で
子供たちを教えている。
about how to fight back
when faced with a harsh fate.
困難な運命に向き合ったとき
どう対処すべきか。
その方法を…。
So education could end a war?
教育で戦が止められるってのか。
きれい事を言うんじゃねえ！
Cut the pretty talk!
What?!
何!?
《こやつも忍!?》
Is he a ninja too?
それはムリだな。
だが よりよき選択肢を選ぶ力を➡
No, that it cannot...
However, perhaps I can
teach them skills
that enable them
to make better choices.
身につけさせることは
できるかもしれん。
お主に問う。 その選択肢とは？
Let me ask you...
What are those choices?
死ぬか生きるかの選択肢よ。
Life or death...
Those are the choices.
ボクに教えられるのは
生き残るための方法だけだ。
The only thing I can teach them
is how to survive.
《それだけでは ダメなんだ。
That's not good enough.
ワシは この世に
平和をなせる変革者を➡
I must choose the revolutionary
who will bring peace to the world.
選ばねばならない…》
この世に破滅をもたらすか➡
To bring destruction upon this world.
今までなかったような
平和に導くか。
Or to bring about a peace which
we have never known before...
それは 皆の心がけ次第だ！
That depends on the commitment
of each and every person!
Hmm... Could this person be...?
《ほう コイツ ひょっとして…》
お主！
Say, you!
You just might be the person
I've been looking for!
ひょっとして
ワシの探している人間かもしれん！
ほう。
Oh...?
What would you do in order
to bring peace to this world?
この世を平和に導くには
どうする？
The world is heading towards
an age of war and strife...
世は戦乱に向かって
動き始めたのだ。
もう止められん。
There's no stopping it.
でも今 心がけ次第と。
You just said it depends on
each person's commitment, didn't you?
どうやれば
この人たちの運命が変わるのだ？
How do we change
these people's destinies?
ただ ひたすら祈りなされ。
Just pray hard.
That is all men can do.
人にできることは それしかない。
《フン…
やはり この男も違ったか》
This man is not the one...either.
今のは!?
What was that?!
これは普通の人たちが住む村。
なぜ忍が!?
This is just an ordinary village!
Why would a ninja...?!
その手裏剣術… お前 風魔だな!?
This shuriken jutsu...
You are from the Fuma, aren't you?!
なぜ
平穏に暮らす人々の村を襲う！
Why attack people who
are living in peace?!
お前も忍だろ。
You are also a ninja.
(自来也)弟子とするべき男と
出会うため旅をしている。
I am journeying in search of the one
who will become my disciple.
フン！ 何を悠長なことを。
Humph! Why waste time
on such a tedious thing?!
今や各国のバランスは崩れ➡
The balance of power between
lands has become shaky
いつ大戦に発展しても
おかしくないという この時期に。
and we are on the verge of
a great war...
あの村も 忍が潜入しているという
情報のもと潰されたのだ。
That village was also destroyed due
to a tip that ninja had infiltrated it.
ただ それだけでか!?
Just because of a tip?!
潰さなければ潰される。
It's destroy, or be destroyed.
ためらったものは
やられる世の中だ。
We live in a world where
you'll die if you hesitate!
《煙玉か！》
A Smoke Bomb!
(自来也)うわっ！ うっ…。
なかなかやるのぉ。
You're pretty good.
お前も忍なら
見逃すことはできぬ。
If you are a ninja too,
I cannot let you live.
あきらめろ！
これがオレたち 忍の運命だ。
Just give up...
This is our fate as ninja.
ひと言 いいか？
Can I say something?
聞く気はねえ。 もう くたばれ!!
I don't feel like listening...
Just...die!!
ワシが あきらめるのを…。
Give up...
あきらめろ。
...on me giving up!
クッ…。
オレを倒しても
また次の刺客が村を襲う。
Even if you bring me down,
another assassin will attack
the village...
オレたちが 呪われた忍の世界に
生きている限り➡
As long as we are cursed to live
in this ninja world,
there will be no peace.
平穏はないぞ。
《ガマ仙人は ワシが➡
The Great Toad Sage's
prophecy said that I am destined
この世に平和をもたらす
変革者を育てることを予言した。
to train the revolutionary
who will bring peace to this world.
しかし ワシはまだ➡
However, I haven't even encountered
this disciple.
その運命の弟子にも
会えずにいる…》
＜ すでに このとき➡
Already at this time,
battles were inevitably being fought.
止めようもない
戦いの連鎖が起こっていた。
自来也もまた
運命と出会う旅を しばし休み➡
Jiraiya was also forced to take
a short break from his journey
木ノ葉の里に
戻らねばならなかった＞
and returned to the Hidden Leaf Village.
戦争だからね 今は。
We're at war...after all.
大蛇丸…。
Orochimaru...
《忍の世から
こんな悲しみをなくすためには➡
In order to erase this sadness
from the ninja world...
ワシが変革者を見つけねば。
I must find the revolutionary...
平和な世を作る者を
選択せねばならんのだ》
I must choose the one
who will bring peace.
＜戦いの炎は
ついに自来也たちまで➡
The flames of war finally drew
in Jiraiya and his comrades.
その渦に いやおうもなく
巻き込むことになる。
これが 後の第三次忍界大戦と
呼ばれる戦いである。
This would come to be known
as the Third Great Ninja War.
自来也たちが
伝説の三忍と呼ばれるのは➡
Shortly afterwards, the three
would come to be known
これより
しばらくしてのことである＞
as the "Legendary Sannin."
Boy, it's not easy coming up with
ideas for writing a book.
The main hero of this book has
seen too much of the ninja world,
(ナツ)『FAIRY TAIL』 前回までは…。
where battle brings
further battle.
(ルーシィ)いつのまにか
カナとはぐれた私は➡
It's a world filled with hate.
七眷属の
華院ヒカルと戦うことになったの。
I want him to somehow
wipe away the hate
(ハッピー)おいらとナツは 途中から
参戦することになったけど➡
and create a world of peace, yet...
ナツは いいとこなかったね。
うっせえ！
Aaah! It's so hard to build up
a story to the climax!
What shall I do?!
でも その場でひらめいた
新必殺技で➡
白だんごをとっちめたぞ！
必殺技ねぇ…。
Next time: "Tales of a Gutsy Ninja -
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 2"